Karol Wypchlo

Senior Full Stack Engineer Warsaw, Poland (UTC+1) linkedin.com/in/karolwypchlo github.com/kwypchlo kwypchlo@gmail.com +48 790 211 247 Full stack engineer, passionate about web3, blockchain, crypto, distributed systems, developer experience and automation. 13 years of experience with web development, react, node.js, docker and infrastructure stack in enterprise and startups.

Work Experience -

Senior Full Stack Engineer

Spaceport Technologies - web3 IP licensing platform

Sep 2023 - Current

Full Stack Engineer on IP licensing platform with blockchain settlement layer.

- refactored web3 authentication on Next.js app with web3auth.io account abstraction and Auth0 SS0 for walletless onboarding
- resolved backend scaling performance issues by improving GraphOL gueries with aggregated blockchain data from The Graph
- cleaned and streamlined component library, theming and responsiveness with Chakra UI based on Figma designs

Software Engineer

Protocol Labs - IPFS and Filecoin blockchain

Nov 2022 - Feb 2023

Software Engineer on Filecoin Saturn project - decentralised web3 CDN for IPFS and Filecoin.

- authored Node.js streamer module processing large files with low memory footprint, failure recovery and resumable batching
- · developed observability api and network monitoring dashboard with data from over 3000 public nginx servers

Senior Full Stack Engineer

Skynet Labs - Sia blockchain

Feb 2020 - Oct 2022

Lead Fullstack Engineer on open source decentralised cloud storage platform - Skynet, built on Sia blockchain network.

- developed multiple React web2 and web3 frontends with Next.js, Gatsby, Vite and CRA
- developed backend Node.js services with Express interacting with Sia and Handshake blockchains through REST and RPC APIs
- designed, built and maintained dockerized Skynet Portal decentralised infrastructure from ground up to 50+ dedicated servers
- authored "Deploy to Skynet" GitHub Action (Node.js) continuous deployment to Skynet network with pull request previews
- developed standalone SiaStream application (compiled Node.js) integrating Fuse with Sia storage optimised for Plex.tv

Senior Javascript Engineer

Crunch.io - survey data analysis

Feb 2017 - Jan 2020

Developed data analysis and visualisation platform for surveys with data grids, visualisations and dashboards, focused on ease of use and user interactions with drag and drop interfaces with react, redux, redux-saga, styled-components, jest and cypress.

- introduced storybook, testing with jest and cypress, prettier, commit hooks, netlify deploys, maintained frontend portion of CI/CD on Jenkins, kept app dependencies up to date, improved webpack build quality and performance
- · learned python basics and helped out with high priority migration of backend service to a new architecture
- after hours project: designed and implemented generic backend SDK API, polyfilling other languages' SDK implementations, saving hundreds of hours of maintenance and development and delivering missing features to key clients

Senior Engineer / Lead

IGT - global leader in gaming

Mar 2015 - Jan 2017

JavaScript engineer, promoted to team lead and tech lead on form-heavy back office AngularJS application.

- · personally introduced model driven forms that allowed rapid development and resulted in on time product delivery
- collaborated with designers on user friendly and modern look of the application with strong emphasis on user experience (hundreds of forms) and mobile friendly design
- since June 2016 assigned as frontend Tech Lead for several projects in IGT responsible for front-end architecture, synergy between teams, code and tools standardisation and communication with management.

Senior Javascript Engineer

Roche - leading biotech company

Dec 2014 - Feb 2015

Developed and maintained internal Backbone frontend application for building websites with drag and drop elements.

Fullstack PHP Developer

Select Sp. z o. o. - software house

Oct 2010 - Nov 2014

- 2013-2014: Lead engineer on Hospital Information System project with Symfony, jQuery and AngularJS
- 2010-2013: multiple CRM deployments based on custom SugarCRM platform (PHP, jQuery)

Education -